<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>The Nose Puncher on Peter Ellinger</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/</link><description>Recent content in The Nose Puncher on Peter Ellinger</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.148.1</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Part 1: A Sentencing Session</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-first-hearing-in-an-alternative-dimension">1. First Hearing in an Alternative Dimension&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nonplussed, I looked at the panel of three hovering above me. The Chairman looked exactly as He had been depicted by Michelangelo: heavy set, energetic and very much in command. His eyes, though, were kindly and a ghost of a twinkle was discernible. The adjudicator sitting to His right wore the uniform of a judge of the Court of Appeal, including a wig; his tall and gaunt figure commanded respect and his solemn expression and demeanour made me shiver. My lifelong friend, Theophil, was sitting to the Chairman’s left. As I turned my eyes to him, he winked, as if to say: “Don’t worry, Peter’le.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 2: Eve</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-meeting-eve">1. Meeting Eve&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An adherence to the chronological order seemed a safe procedure. Accordingly, I went back to the origin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eve was an attractive woman in her mid-thirties. Initially, she was startled by our appearance but soon viewed the tiger with admiration. Theophil had shrunk him to the size of a Burmese cat. Having stroked him affectionately, she turned to me: “He is adorable. But who are you? What brings you here?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 3: First Interlude</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-assessment-of-first-performance">1. Assessment of First Performance&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and Moti welcomed Tiger and me back into the fold. Moti, though, expressed a reservation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Peter’le, why didn’t you explain things to Eve before you punched her?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I thought it best to proceed without delay.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But then you needed Lord Pan’s help!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Moti is right: it was your mission, Peter’le. So why the need for help?” volunteered Archie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But Theophil did not appear until after the mission had been completed. You see, Archie, he did not intervene. He simply helped me to explain. Actually, there was no need to elucidate. By right I was entitled to withdraw the instant I delivered the punch. In the worst case, Eve would have remained puzzled!”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 4: The Herodots</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>(484 – 425 BCE)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-the-punch">1. The Punch&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and I materialised in a market place in Thurii – an Athenian colony during the fifth century BCE. It was a sunny late spring day. Sicily was warm but the light breeze made the heat bearable. Recalling his own days in Syracuse, Archie looked around him with satisfaction. He felt at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tall man, with a balding head and long beard, was surrounded by a group of eager listeners. He was telling them details of the wars between Persia and Greece, referring to the courage of the Spartans at the Thermopylae and the heroics of the Greek navy in Salamis. His voice fell and rose as he talked; and members of the audience applauded whenever he narrated the end of an event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 5: Second Interlude</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-analysing-and-discussing-anachronism">1. Analysing and Discussing Anachronism&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Tiger and Moti welcomed us back enthusiastically. Moti was relieved to find his friend in good shape and unharmed. Giving vent to his joy, he trumpeted. Tiger brushed against Archie’s toga and my slacks. Then, bursting with curiosity, he asked me to tell them all about our venture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I completed my narration, Tiger raised a point that had baffled him. Archie must have been aware that Herodotus had lived before his time. Why then had he expected the historian to be familiar with the name of a mathematician yet to be born?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 6: Qin Shi Huang</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>(ORIGINALLY CALLED YÍNG ZHÈNG)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(260 – 210 BCE)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-punching-qin-shi-huang">1. Punching Qin Shi Huang&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Qin Shi Huang woke from his sleep as soon as the minimised Moti and Peter Gnome materialised in his comfortable bedroom. For a few seconds he pinched his massive arms. Still, he soon realised that his intruders had no physical presence. Otherwise, how could they have dodged the conscientious troopers guarding the entrance to his quarters?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Why do you ride on his back?” he wanted to know after he observed us critically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 7: Third Interlude</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-7/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-moving-to-religions">1. Moving to Religions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“Welcome back from your trip to the East,” observed Tiger as we returned. “What have you achieved?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I punched the greatest tyrant in history and he appreciated my act.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“He must have been a smarty.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“He was!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But you are still in pre-historic times. You know little of that period so that Eve, Herodotus and Qin Shi Huang are readily selected. How will you find appropriate nominees in periods known to you from history classes?” asked Archie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 8: St. Paul</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>(ca. 5 – ca. 64/67 CE)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TO BE CONTINUED&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>