<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>The Nose Puncher on Peter Ellinger</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/</link><description>Recent content in The Nose Puncher on Peter Ellinger</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:51:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Part 1: A Sentencing Session</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-first-hearing-in-an-alternative-dimension">1. First Hearing in an Alternative Dimension&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nonplussed, I looked at the panel of three hovering above me. The Chairman looked exactly as He had been depicted by Michelangelo: heavy set, energetic and very much in command. His eyes, though, were kindly and a ghost of a twinkle was discernible. The adjudicator sitting to His right wore the uniform of a judge of the Court of Appeal, including a wig; his tall and gaunt figure commanded respect and his solemn expression and demeanour made me shiver. My lifelong friend, Theophil, was sitting to the Chairman’s left. As I turned my eyes to him, he winked, as if to say: “Don’t worry, Peter’le.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 2: Eve</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-meeting-eve">1. Meeting Eve&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An adherence to the chronological order seemed a safe procedure. Accordingly, I went back to the origin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eve was an attractive woman in her mid-thirties. Initially, she was startled by our appearance but soon viewed the tiger with admiration. Theophil had shrunk him to the size of a Burmese cat. Having stroked him affectionately, she turned to me: “He is adorable. But who are you? What brings you here?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 3: First Interlude</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-assessment-of-first-performance">1. Assessment of First Performance&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and Moti welcomed Tiger and me back into the fold. Moti, though, expressed a reservation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Peter’le, why didn’t you explain things to Eve before you punched her?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I thought it best to proceed without delay.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But then you needed Lord Pan’s help!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Moti is right: it was your mission, Peter’le. So why the need for help?” volunteered Archie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But Theophil did not appear until after the mission had been completed. You see, Archie, he did not intervene. He simply helped me to explain. Actually, there was no need to elucidate. By right I was entitled to withdraw the instant I delivered the punch. In the worst case, Eve would have remained puzzled!”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 4: The Herodots</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>(484 – 425 BCE)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-the-punch">1. The Punch&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and I materialised in a market place in Thurii – an Athenian colony during the fifth century BCE. It was a sunny late spring day. Sicily was warm but the light breeze made the heat bearable. Recalling his own days in Syracuse, Archie looked around him with satisfaction. He felt at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tall man, with a balding head and long beard, was surrounded by a group of eager listeners. He was telling them details of the wars between Persia and Greece, referring to the courage of the Spartans at the Thermopylae and the heroics of the Greek navy in Salamis. His voice fell and rose as he talked; and members of the audience applauded whenever he narrated the end of an event.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 5: Second Interlude</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-analysing-and-discussing-anachronism">1. Analysing and Discussing Anachronism&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Tiger and Moti welcomed us back enthusiastically. Moti was relieved to find his friend in good shape and unharmed. Giving vent to his joy, he trumpeted. Tiger brushed against Archie’s toga and my slacks. Then, bursting with curiosity, he asked me to tell them all about our venture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I completed my narration, Tiger raised a point that had baffled him. Archie must have been aware that Herodotus had lived before his time. Why then had he expected the historian to be familiar with the name of a mathematician yet to be born?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 6: Qin Shi Huang</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>(ORIGINALLY CALLED YÍNG ZHÈNG)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(260 – 210 BCE)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-punching-qin-shi-huang">1. Punching Qin Shi Huang&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Qin Shi Huang woke from his sleep as soon as the minimised Moti and Peter Gnome materialised in his comfortable bedroom. For a few seconds he pinched his massive arms. Still, he soon realised that his intruders had no physical presence. Otherwise, how could they have dodged the conscientious troopers guarding the entrance to his quarters?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Why do you ride on his back?” he wanted to know after he observed us critically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 7: Third Interlude</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-7/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-moving-to-religions">1. Moving to Religions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“Welcome back from your trip to the East,” observed Tiger as we returned. “What have you achieved?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I punched the greatest tyrant in history and he appreciated my act.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“He must have been a smarty.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“He was!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But you are still in pre-historic times. You know little of that period so that Eve, Herodotus and Qin Shi Huang are readily selected. How will you find appropriate nominees in periods known to you from history classes?” asked Archie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 8: St. Paul</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:12:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>(ca. 5 – ca. 64/67 CE)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-a-chat-with-st-paul">1. A Chat with St. Paul&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Sha’ul of Tarsos – St. Paul to humanity – was surprised when we materialised in front of his eyes in Rome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Are you real or am I seeing things?” he asked&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Depends on your definition of ‘real’. We are here on a mission prescribed by Him and his advisers. But neither of us is alive,” I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Are you then spirits?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 9: Intermezzo</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-9/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:29:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-9/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-two-interlocutory-points">1. Two Interlocutory Points&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Paul’s departure was followed by a council of war. Archie, Moti and Tiger urged me to raise two interlocutory points with the panel. The first concerned my right to delegate the nose punching. The second was whether I could kowtow to or salute the selected person instead of delivering a punch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The panel readily agreed to the second request. They appreciated that my admiration for St. Paul rendered it difficult for me to punch him. The same type of problem could arise in respect of the remaining, chosen, individuals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 10: Livia Augusta</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:34:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>(58 BCE – 29CE)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-calling-on-livia">1. Calling on Livia&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I decided to materialise during Livia’s last year on earth. The once beautiful woman, who captivated Octavius and turned him into the great Augustus, had become a decrepit old woman. Still, her commanding eyes retained their glimmer. She was aware that her appointed day was imminent but kept her natural pride and royal airs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Are you a gladiator?” she wanted to know. “And why do you bring this tiger with you? Is he tame? Why didn’t you leave him behind, in his cage near the amphitheatre?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 11: A Planning Session</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-11/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:34:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-11/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-i-do-fit-in">1. I Do Fit In&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and Moti welcomed us back. To my surprise, Archie stepped forward, shook my hand fervently, and exclaimed: “I sure missed you, Peter’le!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“How come?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You see, originally this haven was created for Moti and me. We welcomed Tiger when he came for a visit and, in due course, asked him to join us. He became and has remained a loyal member of our selective clan.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 12: Genghis Khan</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:34:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>(ca. 1155/1166 - 1227)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-genghis-rise-to-power">1. Genghis Rise to Power&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I was satisfied that Genghis left a mark on humanity. Having unified the warring Mongolian tribes, he beat the Tatars and then proceeded to conquer the North of China. There could be no doubt about his brutality and cruelty. These, though, were inflicted on his enemies. His own mighty horsemen were treated by him with consideration. Unlike Napoleon he spared his troops. Thus, when he broke through the Great Wall he thought it best not to storm it. Instead, he waited patiently until one of the defenders was bribed and opened a gate to him. Genghis demolished part of the wall, paid the agreed bribe to the defector and then had him killed because traitors were despicable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 13: A Council of War</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:34:18 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-13/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-assessment-of-last-encounter">1. Assessment of Last Encounter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Tiger and Moti welcomed us back. They listened eagerly to our account. When we finished, Tiger said that he felt no admiration for Genghis. Moti nodded and observed that fame based on slaughter was akin to notoriety. Still, both of them accepted the greatness of Genghis’ tactics and resolution. They also respected his perseverance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“If a deer chased by a tiger eludes him or runs too fast, he gives up. He does not pursue a risky chase. Genghis did that when he set to cross the Pamir Mountain before familiarising himself with all available routes.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 14: Charles Darwin</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:34:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>(1809 - 1882)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-calling-on-darwin">1. Calling on Darwin&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and I surfaced in 1878. Darwin, who was having an afternoon nap, looked at us with surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“How on earth did you come to my room? I did not hear any knocking. And these strange clothes. From where are you?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Neither of us is alive. You see our ghosts. This here is Archimedes Man of Syracuse. I am sure his name in known to you.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 15: Assessment in Our Haven</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:34:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-15/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-archies-analysis-of-evolution">1. Archie’s Analysis of Evolution&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie and I were teletransported back to our ward on a slow moving beacon. On our way, Archie looked at me thoughtfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Peter’le, why did Darwin and you keep addressing each other by surnames? Why didn’t he call you Peter or Peter’le?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Society was formal in his era. Using a proper name when addressing a person would imply superiority or familiarity. Darwin and I addressed one another as equals. I fell in line with the etiquette of his day.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 16: Second Hearing</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-16/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:51:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-16/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-the-panel-refers-to-fortuna">1. The Panel Refers to Fortuna&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Next morning Theophil summoned me to the second hearing of the panel. To ensure I felt comfortable, Theophil assumed the form of an old friend of my London days, Peppi Stölzl, who had been my late father’s bosom pal in Vienna. Gabriel, too, assumed a new form, which I associated with Maimonides. The Almighty retained his original guise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Well, what do you think of my performance,” I asked with trepidation. Somehow – quite regardless of the verdict – I felt the need of gaining their approval.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 17: Selecting the Last Punchee</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:51:17 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-17/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-how-to-carry-on">1. How to Carry On&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My three comrades greeted me warmly: “We feared you may be sent elsewhere,” said Archie. “In truth, your home is here.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I am delighted to be back,” I confirmed. I then went on and told them all about the hearing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“So now they want you to select a prodigy of the 20th century,” said Archie. “Well, I have read the materials given to me by Lord Pan. The 20th century is marked by a number of outstanding personalities; and you have to pinpoint one of them. To start with, you can divide the candidates into two groups: those you admire and those you detest.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 18: Marie Curie</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-18/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:51:19 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>(1867 – 1934)&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-getting-ready-for-visiting-marie-curie">1. Getting Ready for Visiting Marie Curie&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I decided to visit Marie Curie in April 1934 (a year after my birth). By then, Marie Curie had earned all her medals and honours and also knew she was a very sick woman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the case of other punchees, I appeared accompanied by one of my ward-friends and actually did not change my attire. On this occasion, Archie was not keen to accompany me and both Moti and Tiger declined. Tiger felt that I did not need protection and Moti decided to stay behind with Archie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 19: The Verdict</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 18:51:22 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novels/nose-puncher/part-19/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-back-in-my-haven">1. Back in My Haven&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Archie, Tiger and Moti were pleased to see me back. To my surprise Theophil remained with us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Why did you spirit me away, Maestro?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What else did you want to ask her?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Actually, I was done. Still, she is bound to know that my appearance was not a hallucination. She has the flowers.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“They, too, vanished. And the vase is back in the place in which she used to keep it.”&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>