<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Luck of Valentino on Peter Ellinger</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Luck of Valentino on Peter Ellinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:29:03 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: A Sad Incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:09:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The correspondence respecting the case of Omri Tal  versus Solomon Vered and Movil &amp;amp; Co. Ltd was dumped unceremoniously on my desk late in the morning, on  a  heavily  clouded day in early spring,  by Jacob Keren, sole proprietor of J. Keren &amp;amp; Associates, Advocates, of Rothschild Boulevard,  Tel Aviv.  A short choleric man in his late fifties, with thick glasses,  receding hair and a loud metallic voice, he was – as was his wont – in a foul mood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Teaming with Hannah</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:12:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My choice of Hannah was partly explainable by the friendship I felt for her.  Although Hannah’s solid Hamburgese background differed in more than one way from my relaxed and light-hearted Viennese milieu, both of us were Yekkes. In a firm dominated by Russian Jews and Sabres this cultural affinity drew us together.  Every so often, when we felt alienated by the rough  mannerism  and Chutzpah  of  our colleagues, we reverted to German, earning hostile glances from those present.  In addition, Hannah and I shared a taste for books and for good films. Frequently, we lent German novels to one another and,  occasionally, went together to the cinema. Another, even stranger, bond  was that  both  of us suffered from Asthma. When either of  us  came down with an attack, the other lent a supportive shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Setting Traps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:16:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hannah  spent  two weeks in the dental laboratory  of  an  old acquaintance.  In due course,  Kadmon’s secretary  handed  me the documents received in  respect  of  Omri  Tal’s claim . To my delight, Boaz Tamir had stepped into my trap. The verbose documents served on us had been prepared with a view  to confusing  Kadmon. They failed to state a plain ‘case’ as was appropriate for  a  skirmish  with  down to earth protagonists  like  Hannah  and  me.  Suppressing a malicious grin, I retired to my office to prepare our response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: Justice Ehud Morag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:18:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back  in  my minuscule office, I took stock of the situation. Having the Omri Tal case assigned  to Justice Ehood Morag was an unfortunate development. Although Morag was a  fair minded man and an excellent lawyer, his sympathy was bound to be with the victim of the accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally,  Ehood Morag’s liberal orientation had come as surprise to the legal fraternity of Tel Aviv. Prior to his elevation to the Bench, he  had been  one of the leading advocates engaged by insurance companies in road and industrial accident cases.  He was an accomplished cross-examiner.  He had also been renowned for driving a hard bargain when cases were settled before trial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: My Friendship with Boaz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:19:18 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As  we  walked out, Boaz heaved a sigh of relief. “Ehood Morag gives  me  a  headache. He  has  a  knack  of complicating simple points!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don’t you think his analysis of our case is  right? Isn’t Morag brilliant?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He is; but only in a narrow field,” conceded Boaz. “But  he is unbending and makes no allowances once he steers a course. Judges like  him forget  they  deal  with  human  problems:  not  with  philosophical arguments!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 6: Hannah&#39;s Decision to Change Jobs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:19:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A  few  days passed before I managed to track Hannah down. After weeks of a major  courtroom battle, she took one week of leave. When she  reappeared,  I  stared at her with concern. Once again she  had  lost  weight, looked worn out and a dry cough and persistent wheeze marred her speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You need a real break, Hannah. “And you  ought to spend a few days in Eilat. A change of climate can do wonders.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 7: Pre-Trial Manouverings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:19:26 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During  the  following  weeks, Boaz and  I  kept  exchanging  procedural broadsides.  Each clever move cancelled out another, which meant that we produced more heat than light. The  proceedings,  though,  did  not disrupt our friendship. During the very same period, I came over regularly  to the  Tamirs’ residence, usually bringing with me a bottle of wine or, as was  the custom in Israel, fresh fruit for their table. Invariably, we had  a pleasant time, playing after dinner a game of Monopoly, listening to music, or discussing fervently some political events or newly published books. The  only subject we stayed clear off  was the Omri Tal trial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 8: Justice Baruch Shoham</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:19:34 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Boaz returned to work, winter was just around the corner. Our  pre-trial  hearing with  Baruch Shoham took place on a wet and chilly day.    Unlike  the sparkling  conference table in Morag’s ante chamber, Shoham’s plain table  was covered  with  books,   untidily strewn files and proofs  of  articles  to  be published  in  The  Advocate, which he edited for our  Law  Society.  As  we entered, he raised his eyes from the document in front of him and beckoned us to sit down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 9: Boaz&#39;s Setback</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:24:33 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leaving  our  briefcases  in the “robing room”, Boaz  and  I walked  to Nahalat  Benjamin Street. Ignoring Boaz’s covetous glance in the direction of David Mizrachi’s Eatery, I steered a course to the old fashioned  restaurant which served home cooked Jewish  dishes.  Boaz sighed  as  he perused the bill of fares but cheered up when  the  salt  beef, boiled chicken, mashed potatoes and a mixed salad were placed in front of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 10: Pre-Trial Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:24:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Omri  Tal  saw  Dr. Alon Shaked before the end of the  month.  When  the medical report was in, I convened the firm’s pre-trial ‘conference’, chaired by Jacob Keren in person. Shortly before the appointed hour, Hannah Hod slipped into  my  office. She  looked invigorated, had put on weight and, to my delight, had  taken  the trouble to make herself up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And how are you, Eli? I hear you have moved up in the world?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 11: The Trial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:24:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some  three weeks after our conference with Keren, Hannah and I  marched over to our dilapidated court building.  Boaz  looked well and at ease. In contrast, Omri Tal, who was sitting  next  to  him, appeared  nervous,  even apprehensive. He was talking in  undertone  with  the singularly attractive girl, who was doing her best to calm him down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Glad  to  see  everybody’s  on deck,” said  Baruch  Shoham,  having  responded graciously when all of us rose to our feet and bowed as he entered the  court room  from his chambers. Unlike the attorneys, who continued to  wear  gowns, the judge’s formal attire comprised a black silk jacket, a white shirt with  a stiff collar and a sober tie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 12: Meanderings During the Recess</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:24:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As  soon as the judge left the Courtroom, Boaz  departed in the company of Omri and his attractive fiancée.  Hannah  left in a hurry, mumbling she  had to report to Ruth Schwartz.  Fearing  David Mizrachi’s eatery would be crowded, I crossed the road to a nearby sandwiches and coffee bar. Munching away, I started to soliloquise about the events of  the morning and about the legal fraternity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My years with Jacob Keren’s firm convinced me that law  and drama  coincided  mainly  in films and in poorly written books. Undoubtedly, every trial had had  its  tense and often  unpredictable moment. But I had never seen a witness crumbling in the  box and  coming up with a tearful confession. Most trials were less momentous than the Omri Tal case. Victory  was  secured  by careful  preparation,  sound  tactics  and skilful  arguments.  On  many occasions the final result was dictated by sheer luck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 13: Settlement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:24:45 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 2.45 p.m., Hannah, Boaz and myself rose as Baruch Shoham took his place at the head of the conference table in his chambers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well,” he said benignly, “I hope everybody had a pleasant lunch?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thank you, Judge,” Hannah assured him on behalf of all present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And have you had any discussion  about a suitable figure?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are still rather apart, Judge,” volunteered Hannah. “I believe both parties would like to have your view on the matter.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 14: Post Mortem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:29:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eager  to  make her report to Ruth Schwartz, Hannah  left  straightaway. Boaz  and I spent some time drafting the settlement document and then  walked back  together, wadding our way through the thin, aggravating, drizzle. As  if by agreement, we dropped into David Mizrachi’s eatery. Lunch time was long over but both  of  us  felt the need for a cup of his strong  brewed  aromatic  coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What was that odd crack about Shalom Cohen?” I asked as I wiped the raindrops off my face. “I didn’t know Hannah and Omri had common friends?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 15: Planning Our Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:29:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/legal-episodes/the-luck-of-valentino/part-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Well Eli,” said Boaz after a short lull. “This is a good a time to bring up  a point I wanted to raise with you for a while. As you say:  Keren’s  firm isn’t paradise; ditto for Israel Silver’s outfit. Why don’t we  make ourselves independent?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Start  a  new practice? There  are some two hundred law firms  in  Tel Aviv?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Even  so,  don’t  you think we can make it? We had good  training;  and  we’ve worked well together as a team in law school!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
