<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Bright Lion on Peter Ellinger</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/</link><description>Recent content in Bright Lion on Peter Ellinger</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:55:53 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preface</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/preface/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:40:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/preface/</guid><description>&lt;p>The object of Bright Lion is to compare two approaches to Judaism. Whilst both are imbued with tolerance and understanding they are nevertheless distinct. One approach is that of the tolerant traditional observer who follows the commands of his faith but is not perturbed by the transgressions and by the non-conformity of fellow Jews. The other approach is that of a sceptic who doubts many of the tenets of the faith as well as the Bible’s historicity and does not observe commands he fails to understand. His adherence to Judaism is based on his acceptance of the ethnic affiliation of members of the community. He is tolerant of the view of orthodox believers, provided they do not attempt to force him to adopt their orientation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 1: Getting Started</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:41:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-visit-to-yentls-grave">1. Visit to Yentl’s Grave&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Earlier today I resolved to write my autobiography. I was mulling the idea over since the day Yentl came up with it. She had just finished reading the memoirs of an American politician. She thought his style was good and had appreciated his anecdotes. But, she asked, why did he presume others had an interest in his mundane manoeuvrings and dull existence on the fringes of Washington D.C.?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 2: Youth in Israel</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:43:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="2-an-odd-jobs-boy">2. An Odd Jobs Boy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Father passed away a few weeks before my eighth birthday. My brother David was just three years old. I stood by the still uncovered grave, beside Mother who was crying. My eyes, in contrast, remained dry. What I recall most vividly is my impatience to go home because I thought that David, who had remained in the care of a neighbour, might need me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As yet, the meaning of our loss had not dawned on me. I knew, of course, that I was not going to see my smiling, active and supportive Father ever again. He would no longer pat my shoulder and grin proudly when I showed him my school grades. He had gone – so Mother said – to a better world where he would know no sorrow or pain. The effect that his death was bound to have on us – the constraints of a family without a breadwinner and the ensuing financial problems – were beyond my grasp.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 3: Settling Down in Tel Aviv</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:46:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="7-employment-and-my-first-marriage">7. Employment and My First Marriage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After the trip with Bushi and the culmination of the Suez Crisis I looked for a job. Financially, I could have stuck to my existing enterprises; they were sound. My ambition though was for a future on the stage. Bennie Ornan kept encouraging me to apply for a position in the army’s Entertainment Corps. He was convinced that my medical misadventure did not present an obstacle. I was, however, perturbed by the realisation that the Corps’ main object was indoctrination. I wanted to devote myself to art. For that reason I did not send feelers to TA.1. I knew that a teacher’s career was well paid and satisfactory. I knew also that, if I joined TA.1, Sheen would encourage me to perform shows. My ambition, though, remained the theatre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 4: Based in New York</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:52:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-4/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="10-i-change-my-name-to-loeb-zohar">10. I Change my Name to Loeb Zohar&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When I think today, as an aged retiree, about my returning to the status of a student, I feel I took a leap into the dark. In reality, my positions, at the ITV and before it at Tichon, were good. To change course at such a late stage involved courage and an optimistic outlook. I am glad I had them and have no regrets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 5: Retirement</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:54:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="14-move-to-safed">14. Move to Safed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I returned to Brooklyn with the intention of giving up my position and proceeding to my retirement haven in Safed. I was now 65 years of age and sensed that my heydays were over and my bright youth in Tichon was far behind me. Nonetheless, my values and orientation on life had not changed. Throughout my journey I remained a non-fanatical and liberal believer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I conveyed my decision to Avner a few days after I made my final resolution to leave. For all practical purposes he was ready to take my place. He had completed his studies with flying colours, had proved himself as cantor and had delivered a number of sermons after prayer sessions. His style, though, differed from mine. He tended to concentrate on the topics covered by him without adding jokes or plays on words. In reality, his approach was more serious and traditional than mine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 6: End of Journey</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:55:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-6/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="17-ithaca">17. Ithaca&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It was a dismal day. The skies were cloudy and it started to drizzle. All the same, I was set to walk over to the cemetery to visit Yentl’s grave. Apart from the flowers – a lovely bunch of Dahlias – I was going to take with me a copy of the manuscript. She had prompted me to write my autobiography. It was, accordingly, only right to bring her a copy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>