<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Job: A Reassessment on Peter Ellinger</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Job: A Reassessment on Peter Ellinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:57:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Sources and Background</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:56:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before turning to the discussion of the &lt;em&gt;Book of Job&lt;/em&gt; {hereafter: “&lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt;”; the hero’s name is spelt as “&lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt;” [in Roman letters]}it is important to refer to the extant texts available to us. The one usually cited is the Masoretic Text (“MT”) version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scholars believe that it was composed during the 5th or early 4th century BCE, that is, before the Hashmonean period. The book is unlikely to have been composed earlier than that. It is true that the issue discussed in it – that is, the theodicy issue – was raised by Jeremiah [Jer. 12:1-3]. However, the 6th century – covering this prophet’s long ministry – witnessed the struggle of Judah with Babylon and the final destruction of Jerusalem by Nebuchadnezzar followed by the exile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: The Structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:57:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At first glance, Job’s structure appears straightforward. Chapter 1 and 2 – the prologue – are complemented by the epilogue – Chapter 42 (verses 7-end). They are written in easy to comprehend prose, similar to that of Esther.[^22] They were, it is generally believed, written by the very hand which added captions or introductory statements to the ensuing text. By way of illustration take verse 1 and the first words of verse 2 of chapter 3, which read: “After this Iyyov [Job] opened his mouth and cursed his day. And [Job] spoke and said …”. The remaining part of verse 2 and the rest of the chapter are  poetic and differ from the explanatory caption preceding them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: The Framework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:57:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/job_reassessment/part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The prologue and epilogue are expressed in readable and elegant prose. The first chapter describes Job’s piety and orthodoxy and then refers to the day on which ‘the sons of god’ congregated in His front. It adds that ‘Satan’ came with them and that he questioned the motive of Job’s piety, alleging that it was due to the protection and prosperity conferred on him by divinity. Satan says that if these were taken from Job, he would curse God ‘to [His] face’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
