<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Welcome to my collection of stories on Peter Ellinger</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to my collection of stories on Peter Ellinger</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:41:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1: Reminiscences at the Station in Munich</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:18:14 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-the-platform-phenomenon">1. The Platform Phenomenon&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An event that took place in an underground-train station in Munich’s inner city had far reaching effects on the life of three persons: Peppi Stölzl – who rose thereafter in the world, became Sir Joseph-Dieter, Freiherr von Stölzenfeld – my late father, Robert Berger, known to friends as ‘Tommy’, and myself, Peter Berger, a mendicant professor who eventually settled in Singapore but travelled from time to time to London where eventually I met Peppi,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Legal Publications</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/about-me/legal-pubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:57:54 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/about-me/legal-pubs/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="list-of-peter-ellingers-publications-on-legal-topics">List of Peter Ellinger’s Publications on Legal Topics&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="books-and-book-length-chapters-in-co-authored-books">&lt;ins>Books and Book-Length Chapters in Co-Authored Books&lt;/ins>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Documentary Letters of Credit&lt;/em> - A Comparative Study (revised D. Phil. thesis, comparing English, American, French and German law); University of Singapore Press, 1970, li + 389 pp.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“&lt;em>Bills of Exchange and Banking&lt;/em>” being Chapter 3 of Vol. 2 of Chitty on Contracts; London, Sweet and Maxwell: 23rd ed., 1968, pp. 162 - 242; 24th ed., 1977, p. 135 - 278; 25th ed., 1983, pp. 2451 - 2588; 26th ed., 1989, pp. 179 - 390; 27th ed, 1994, [Chap. 33], pp. 173 – 391, 27th ed. 1999, [Chap. 33], pp. 170 – 379; 28th ed., 1999, [Chap. 34], pp. 169-376 (plus 3rd Supp.); 29th ed. 2004 [Chap 34; with Prof. R.H.A. Hooley], pp. 253 – 497.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 1: Arrival and Vigil</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 12:12:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-pension-kegel">1. Pension Kegel&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The electric car of Pension Kegel was waiting for me outside the railway station. Fastening my scarf to keep out the crisp air of a typical dawn in Zermatt, I walked briskly up the platform and got in. As often before, I breathed the clean air in deeply and with satisfaction. The absence of fuel driven motorcars was a blessing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The electric car driver, who was also the sole concierge of the modest establishment, manoeuvred his ramshackle vehicle adroitly through the narrow and winding lanes of my favourite Swiss resort. I observed with a grim smile that for him, too, time had not stood still: his wrinkles had deepened and his hair had turned silver grey. Bestowing on me the smile reserved for old customers, he carried my suitcase up the stairs to the reception counter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preface</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/preface/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:40:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/preface/</guid><description>&lt;p>The object of Bright Lion is to compare two approaches to Judaism. Whilst both are imbued with tolerance and understanding they are nevertheless distinct. One approach is that of the tolerant traditional observer who follows the commands of his faith but is not perturbed by the transgressions and by the non-conformity of fellow Jews. The other approach is that of a sceptic who doubts many of the tenets of the faith as well as the Bible’s historicity and does not observe commands he fails to understand. His adherence to Judaism is based on his acceptance of the ethnic affiliation of members of the community. He is tolerant of the view of orthodox believers, provided they do not attempt to force him to adopt their orientation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 1: A Dilemma</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 20:10:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>My secretary had arranged the incoming mail in a neat pile. As I leafed through it, my glance fell on an envelope posted in Colombo. Was it a request for a reference from one of my recent Sri Lankan students? I was about to slice the cover open when Shamsiah’s call reminded me that my Banking Law class was to commence in five minutes. Reluctantly, I dropped the letter back on my desk, picked up my notes and hurried to my seminar room.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 1: Above the Clouds</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:57:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-an-extraordinary-catalogue">1. An Extraordinary Catalogue&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As the aeroplane steadied on its westward course, I started to skim through the papers respecting the legal entanglement that required my presence in London. Conscience and professional integrity dictated that I peruse the bundle meticulously. I owed this to the friendly law firm that was paying handsomely for my services and for the comfortable seat in the business class section of British Airways’ direct flight from Singapore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Mayhem and the Brotherhood of Man</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:23:14 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-the-locum-and-his-provocation">1. The Locum and his Provocation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After his reunion with Peppi, Dad had to travel to Italy. On his return to the old Bavarian capital, Dad took the train to Peppi’s station. Upon disembarking, he saw a strange figure mounting the podium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Where is Peppi Stölzl?” he asked the new incumbent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’m standing in for him this morning,” came the laconic reply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I was hoping to see him here today.” Dad let his disappointment show.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Self-Published Books</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/about-me/self-pubs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 13:00:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/about-me/self-pubs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;ins>Peter Ellinger Self-Published Books&lt;/ins>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A Candid Obituary (2006)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Devil in Munich (2007)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Bowing Harlequin (2007)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reunion in Zermatt (2008)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Scales of Fortuna (2010)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Counter Bible (2016)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ephemeral Stories (2017)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Down Memory Lane (2018)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Bright Lion (2020)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Nose Puncher (2022)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>All these books were published by Conet Printing. The copyright is vested in Peter Ellinger.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Planning a Historical Trial</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 12:14:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-josephus-and-the-great-jewish-revolt">1. Josephus and the Great Jewish Revolt&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I doubt if Pilkin and I would have become mates had it not been for the Josephus Flavius trial staged by TA.1 in 1950. Although the War of Independence was by then long over, Israel had not fully recovered from its economic and social effects. Commodities were scarce, prices were high and the black market was booming. One of the objectives of Israeli schools of that period was to turn its pupils into good citizens. Nobody was held in greater contempt than a traitor to the struggle for the survival of the two years old nation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 1: Getting Started</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:41:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-visit-to-yentls-grave">1. Visit to Yentl’s Grave&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Earlier today I resolved to write my autobiography. I was mulling the idea over since the day Yentl came up with it. She had just finished reading the memoirs of an American politician. She thought his style was good and had appreciated his anecdotes. But, she asked, why did he presume others had an interest in his mundane manoeuvrings and dull existence on the fringes of Washington D.C.?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: A Gifted Youth</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:49:15 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>My knowledge of Ranjan’s youth is based on what he thought fit to tell me and on occasional remarks of his contemporaries. A model primary school pupil, a boy scouts leader and a fine cricket player were on the credit side. A tricky fellow, one ready to snitch when it suited him, and a mercenary to boot, were remarks made by those who disliked him. One of them told me that Ranjan would display enthusiasm when he was the key figure in some sporting event, but often lost interest when it was the turn of others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Past Perfect</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:59:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="3-a-confused-day">3. A Confused Day&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Bill Riggs was waiting for me at the arrival hall of Terminal 3 at Heathrow Airport. He was, actually, looking fresher and more vigorous than he had ever appeared in Singapore. For a short while we gossiped about mutual friends in Singapore, about my forthcoming book and about his own work in his London firm. Then, as if by prior arrangement, we turned to business. I started by expressing my doubts respecting the outcome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: An Antiques Dealer in Munich</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:25:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-peppis-second-career">1. Peppi’s Second Career&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Following this encounter, Peppi started to go from strength to strength. His friendship with Dad remained intact, with each rejoicing at the other’s success. Their paths, though, did not cross again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Dad, the turning point was Russia’s withdrawal from Vienna in 1951. He and Peppi saw in it Theophil’s hand. Modern historians have come up with a more mundane explanation: Russia’s bridgehead in Vienna was of no military, political or tactical advantage. Austria’s unilateral declaration of neutrality – the price exacted by the Russians for their withdrawal – constituted a safer barrier against Western aggression than the sparse Red Army troops stationed in the old Habsburg capital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: Learning the Law: Courts and Keren</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:13:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-we-attend-trials">1. We Attend Trials&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our teacher granted us leave to attend court hearings during three mornings dominated by classes on science. As Pilkin’s home was not far from the District Court building, I went to pick him up early in the morning. His mother’s unadorned poorly furnished flat on the top floor of a run down apartment block made me gape. Obviously, his late father had not left them well off. Embarrassed, I remembered Shosh had told me that, when opportunity presented itself, Pilkin and his young brother, David, carried out odd jobs, such as deliveries, doubling up for newspaper vendors and occasional home repairs. To my relief, Pilkin appeared unaware of my consternation. He watched with satisfaction as I sipped the cup of hot and aromatic lemon tea his mother brought me and then showed me, with relish, his small but neatly organised and catalogued collection of coins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 2: Youth in Israel</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:43:13 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="2-an-odd-jobs-boy">2. An Odd Jobs Boy&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Father passed away a few weeks before my eighth birthday. My brother David was just three years old. I stood by the still uncovered grave, beside Mother who was crying. My eyes, in contrast, remained dry. What I recall most vividly is my impatience to go home because I thought that David, who had remained in the care of a neighbour, might need me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As yet, the meaning of our loss had not dawned on me. I knew, of course, that I was not going to see my smiling, active and supportive Father ever again. He would no longer pat my shoulder and grin proudly when I showed him my school grades. He had gone – so Mother said – to a better world where he would know no sorrow or pain. The effect that his death was bound to have on us – the constraints of a family without a breadwinner and the ensuing financial problems – were beyond my grasp.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: The City of the Lion</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:50:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Agnes turned out to be a vivacious English-educated Chinese, some five or six years older than Ranjan. A telephone call she received when I delivered Ranjan’s parcel convinced me that my friend was not the only man in her life. Out of curiosity, I accepted her invitation to a party in her flat but, in the event, left early as I found it difficult to fit with her guests. Still, before long I met colleagues, mainly from the English literature department, with whom I was able to mix.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: Along the Rhine</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:04:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="12-her-loreley">12. ‘Her Loreley’&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A classy BMW, booked by Yuan Ming in London, was waiting for us on our arrival in Cologne airport. I was relieved when one of the firm’s employees offered to drive us through the hectic traffic of the town to the shore of the Rhine. A tour of the dome was complemented by our lengthy visit to the nearby Germanic museum, a modern structure encapsulating a Roman mosaic. It was laid bare in the bombing attacks of 1944 after being hidden under the ground for over a thousand years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4: Anna's Defection and Helga's Death</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:26:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-4/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-annas-change-of-heart">1. Anna&amp;rsquo;s Change of Heart&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anna was growing up. Occasionally she brought up subjects she had never raised before. Some related to human relationships. Others touched on faith and religion. Peppi recalled, in particular, a conversation they had one evening on their way home. They had been shocked to witness a van knocking a young man off his motorcycle. Once they had recovered, they continued their walk home. Then, unexpectedly, Anna asked: “Papa, does the Good Lord really exist?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4: The Josephus Trial</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:18:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I stretched myself comfortably on the bed in Pension Kegel in Zermatt, I kept musing on my days with law firms and in universities. The foundation was laid when, some three years after our initial encounter, Jacob Keren accepted me as a trainee. During the years I had spent with him, I learned much about the law and life in general. By the time I left Israel, I had – under Keren’s guidance – developed a penchant for rescuing losing cases. That gift stood me in good stead during my years in Wellington, in Melbourne and in Singapore. All the same, my greatest success as a lawyer remained the trial of Josephus Flavius in TA.1. Smilingly, I allowed myself to stray back to it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 3: Settling Down in Tel Aviv</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:46:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="7-employment-and-my-first-marriage">7. Employment and My First Marriage&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After the trip with Bushi and the culmination of the Suez Crisis I looked for a job. Financially, I could have stuck to my existing enterprises; they were sound. My ambition though was for a future on the stage. Bennie Ornan kept encouraging me to apply for a position in the army’s Entertainment Corps. He was convinced that my medical misadventure did not present an obstacle. I was, however, perturbed by the realisation that the Corps’ main object was indoctrination. I wanted to devote myself to art. For that reason I did not send feelers to TA.1. I knew that a teacher’s career was well paid and satisfactory. I knew also that, if I joined TA.1, Sheen would encourage me to perform shows. My ambition, though, remained the theatre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4: A Trip to Oxford</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:51:33 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few weeks later, I had proof of the validity of their assessment. Notwithstanding my heavy teaching load and other commitments in Singapore, I had been working steadily on my doctoral thesis. Our library’s holding were adequate for my research of the English and Commonwealth law in point but, as was to be expected, had few materials from other jurisdictions. To get them, I had to spend some time in Oxford.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4: Settlements</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:07:14 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-4/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="14-exciting-auction">14. Exciting Auction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“You look refreshed,” said Bill Riggs when I arrived next morning in his office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Thanks. And how does the case stand?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Our Judge is back in action. In the pre-trial conference, he urged the parties to settle!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“And have you?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Whitehead and Blackburn won’t let us,” he said, referring to the two fighting cocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What’s the matter with those two?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“They had a quarrel – a shouting match – over the Wine Stewardship of their club. Since then they are not on speaking terms.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 5: Peppi's Last Days in Munich</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:37:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-sale-of-the-munich-business">1. Sale of the Munich Business&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Peppi decorated his new flat to his own taste. The Albigensian panel painting, which prior to Helga’s death had been kept out of sight, now adorned the wall of his study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shortly after moving into his new flat, Peppi received two letters. Anna wrote to say she had completed her secretarial studies and had accepted a well-paid post in one of Bremen’s leading industrial firms. She thanked him for his support in the past but emphasised that she was relieved to be able, at long last, to ‘stand on her own two feet’. Peppi’s reply, congratulating her on her achievement, was laconic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 5: Early Years of Friendship. Pilkin's Heart Attack</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:19:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-a-budding-actor">1. A Budding Actor&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In most regards, my success at the trial remained a Pyhrric victory. In the minds of the public, a worn cliché – “there is no smoke without fire” – defeated the logical argument. Josephus’ reputation remained as tarnished as ever. All the same, the historical trial of the long deceased historian constituted a milestone in my career. Recalling it vividly during the dinner in Pension Kegel, some 45 years after the event, I concluded that the prelude to the great football match remained my neatest achievement as a lawyer. Single handed, I had won a battle that took place in an unsympathetic, even prejudiced, forum. Relaxing in Pension Kegel’s comfortable sitting room as I sipped a cup of aromatic coffee, I mused on the episode and on the major effect it introduced into my erstwhile lonesome existence: it cemented a bond between Pilkin and myself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 4: Based in New York</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:52:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-4/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="10-i-change-my-name-to-loeb-zohar">10. I Change my Name to Loeb Zohar&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When I think today, as an aged retiree, about my returning to the status of a student, I feel I took a leap into the dark. In reality, my positions, at the ITV and before it at Tichon, were good. To change course at such a late stage involved courage and an optimistic outlook. I am glad I had them and have no regrets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 5: End of Era</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:52:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the surface, my friendship with Ranjan remained intact. Inwardly, though, I had misgivings. Jilting a girl was one thing; holding onto money given by the girl in anticipation of a union, put a different connotation on the episode. I knew for certain that, in similar circumstances, I should have restored the money to her family. Keeping it was both inappropriate and improper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this score, Ranjan showed no remorse. Risking both his own savings as well as Lillo’s bequest, he continued to dabble in the local stock exchange. Bank statements he showed me in confidence indicated that he was making steady gains.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 6: Peppi Moves to London (Theophil's Antique)</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:27:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peppi arrived in London just in time to celebrate his seventy-fifth birthday. Despite his advanced age, Peppi adjusted to his new environment in no time. Soon he felt at home both in Hampstead and in Kensington Church Street. With the joint efforts of father and daughter, Theophil’s Antiques continued to flourish. Within two years, they had taken over all the shopping space in the house. To facilitate further expansion, Peppi purchased the building.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 6: Our European Trip</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:25:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-6/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-turkey">1. Turkey&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It took us just over two years to save enough money. By then, I had nearly finished my pupillage at Jacob Keren &amp;amp; Associates. Pilkin was slogging his way through his course at the Hebrew University and making every effort to shine on the stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sipping a second glass of Cognac in the comfortable dining room in Pension Kegel, I recalled with amusement the unadorned berth my friend and I had taken on a Turkish ship sailing along the coast of Anatolia to Istanbul. It had been a no-frills trip marked by the need to economise. Yet, despite the parsimony dictated by our circumstances, our adventure had left a deeper impression on me than the many high class tours and neatly planned excursions I had enjoyed later on in life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 5: Retirement</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:54:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="14-move-to-safed">14. Move to Safed&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I returned to Brooklyn with the intention of giving up my position and proceeding to my retirement haven in Safed. I was now 65 years of age and sensed that my heydays were over and my bright youth in Tichon was far behind me. Nonetheless, my values and orientation on life had not changed. Throughout my journey I remained a non-fanatical and liberal believer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I conveyed my decision to Avner a few days after I made my final resolution to leave. For all practical purposes he was ready to take my place. He had completed his studies with flying colours, had proved himself as cantor and had delivered a number of sermons after prayer sessions. His style, though, differed from mine. He tended to concentrate on the topics covered by him without adding jokes or plays on words. In reality, his approach was more serious and traditional than mine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 6: Ranjan's Perspective</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:52:46 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>During my years in Wellington, I often soliloquised about Ranjan’s life. Years later, when we had returned to Singapore, I felt the need to clear my mind. My occasional talks with Tay Fung-Shuo, which I had during my first period in Singapore, threw no light on the episodes respecting Ranjan. Tay had remained tight lipped and, as soon as decorum permitted, changed the subject, usually by leading the way to some newly discovered antique porcelain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 7: Peppi's Delve Into Porcelain</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:27:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Theophil’s Antiques continued to go from strength to strength as did Peppi’s fame. He was delighted when one of London University’s Colleges conferred on him an Honorary Doctorate. Another source of joy was Lucy’s appointment as an Adjunct Professor in another College. Initially, Peppi was concerned about her drained appearance when she returned home after her classes. To his relief she soon adjusted to her position, carrying on her new duties without neglecting their shop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 7: The Rendezvous</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:13:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-7/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-leah">1. Leah&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Early next morning, as the Matterhorn emerged in its splendour at the first rays of light, I resumed my vigil. Soon the electric cars started to arrive from the station but the patrons alighting from them bore no resemble to my Pilkin of old. By 9.00 a.m. I threw in the towel. For all I knew, Pilkin might be snoring in a comfortable room in some other hotel in Zermatt. Despite his formidable size, he constituted a needle not easily pinpointed in the haystack of the buoyant flow of tourists in the popular resort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Part 6: End of Journey</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 14:55:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novels/bright-lion/part-6/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="17-ithaca">17. Ithaca&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>It was a dismal day. The skies were cloudy and it started to drizzle. All the same, I was set to walk over to the cemetery to visit Yentl’s grave. Apart from the flowers – a lovely bunch of Dahlias – I was going to take with me a copy of the manuscript. She had prompted me to write my autobiography. It was, accordingly, only right to bring her a copy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 7: An Aspiring Politician</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:55:17 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is time to turn back to my years in Wellington. The geographic remoteness did not distance Ranjan and me from one another. We corresponded periodically but, of course, had less occasion for exchanges of views and of impressions than during our days in Oxford and in Singapore. Each was preoccupied with his own career. I tried hard to settle in the windy capital of New Zealand. My problems were related mainly to my family life and to the occasional hiccups of academia. Ranjan sought to rise in his home country. His new milieu and environment were alien to me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 8: Peppi Meets Peter Berger</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:29:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>Initially, Peppi’s new venture attracted limited interest. London was blessed with a number of well-established shops specialising in European ceramics. In addition, many experienced collectors tended to acquire their pieces at auctions. Peppi, though, had learned to bide his time and could afford to be patient. The modest profit made by the end of the second year of the ceramics venture signalled that he was on the right track. A few months thereafter his enterprise gained further momentum when two adjacent porcelain shops closed down. Peppi acquired the stock-in-trade of both dealers and, as anticipated, their customers turned to his shop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 8: Intermezzo</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:16:02 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-8/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-meandering-about-life">1. Meandering About Life&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As I relaxed over lunch in a booth table in the mountain establishment on the Riffelalp, I kept reflecting on the forty years that had passed since the days spent by Pilkin and me in Zermatt. Professionally, I had made it. Although I was not destined to develop into a court room virtuoso, it had not taken me long to rise from strength to strength in Jacob Keren &amp;amp; Associates. Initially, I had worked with Hannah Hod, the scion of an old Jewish family from Hamburg, who was a few years my senior. We won many of our cases and, in the process, developed a good, even if unromantic, friendship.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 8: A Spiteful Reaction</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-8/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:56:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ranjan was rising in politics, continued to make a fortune at the Bar and laid the foundation for the great leap forward. He refrained from referring to his marriage but once mentioned in passing that there was no sign of a ‘family’. I drew my conclusions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My own life, too, continued uneventfully. Then, one day, Pat spotted an advertisement for a new Chair of Law at Monash University in Melbourne. She nagged me into applying and – with the help of Fortuna – I got the job.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 9: Encounter with Mr. X: Alias Friedrich Duval</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:31:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>My friendship with Peppi and Lucy filled a gap in my life as well as in theirs. Usually, I packed my suitcase with joy for the flight to London and with a glum face for the return trip back to my barren home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could fill a whole ‘bundle’ with anecdotes from my visits to London. Despite his advanced age, Peppi had retained his zest for life and his keen intellect; and he was full of fun. Lucy too was an excellent companion. Occasionally, when Peppi was reluctant to go out in the evening, the two of us went to the West End on our own. After the show, we would have a snack or a drink in one of the numerous bars where, often, I listened with admiration to Lucy’s witty critique of the performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 9: Reunion. Reminiscences</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:18:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-9/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-we-meet">1. We Meet&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>My neatly tailored three piece grey suit, white shirt and fashionable tie did little to ease the pounding of my heart as I followed the concierge through the imposing dining room of the Zermattschein. Would I recognise Pilkin as soon as I spotted our table? Had his appearance changed as much as mine? For all I knew, he could by now have become the heart and soul of parties given in his honour by a group of jolly grandchildren!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 9: Jaffna</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-9/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:58:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the end of my year of leave, we returned to Melbourne. I had to complete a few additional years of service so as to secure an adequate retirement benefit. I assured Pat that, in due course, we would move back to Singapore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this second spell at Monash, Marcus kept me informed about Ranjan. Politically, Ranjan moved from strength to strength. Within a few years, he became the President’s right-hand man. He was now tipped ‘the successor’ and, in his own way, wielded power and influence. But – all in all – he had remained a subordinate. The reigns were still in his superior’s hands. Occasionally, Australian television showed him in the company of other members of the Sri Lankan cabinet, assembled around their leader and ready to run his errands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 10: Peppi's Last Years and Dillma</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:33:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peppi, Lucy and I used to take long walks on Hampstead Heath or in Kensington Gardens. From time to time, when the weather permitted, I hired a car and drove us down to St Albans, Windsor or Oxford and, on many a fine spring day, to Hampton Court. Like most visitors, we continued to get lost in the maze and invariably had to wait, with the rest of the crowd, to be guided out by one of the warders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 10: Pilkin's Odyssey</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:26:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-10/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-pilkins-remaining-years-in-israel">1. Pilkin’s Remaining Years in Israel&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>At this point, the waiter wheeled in a trolley with our main courses. As soon as he departed – having re-filled our wine glasses – I said: “Well, now it’s your turn, mon Cher Pilkin – or shall I say Rabbi Zohar?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“At you service,” he smiled benignly. “And ‘Pilkin’ will do!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“So out with it!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Where shall I start?” he asked, smacking his lips as he savoured the excellent goose.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 10: Alfie's Verdict</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:59:39 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many years have passed since that fateful turn of events, covering Ranjan’s act of revenge and the atrocities committed in Jaffna. But even after Ranjan’s untimely death at the hand of a hired assassin, my mind kept mulling through the episode. One evening I slid to my antiques room in Singapore so as to discuss the matter with Tay Fung-Shuo – now replaced by his porcelain Doppelgänger, dubbed Alfie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“So you do old antiques dealer honour of unexpected visit,” Alfie chided me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epilogue</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/epilogue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:10:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/epilogue/</guid><description>&lt;p>The penultimate draft of &lt;em>The Hidden Rooms&lt;/em> was completed when I was in my sixties. In 2010 I self-published it as part of &lt;em>The Scales of Fortuna&lt;/em>. Nowadays, when I am in my nineties, I have revised it with a view to uploading in my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much has happened in the decades that had elapsed. Following my return to Singapore, I maintained a regular correspondence with Brian Davies. Before long, he made his exit from the City and, as planned, opened an art dealership with his daughter’s friend. All seemed clear on his horizon. His business was thriving. Then, one sad day, I received the death notice of his wife, Ruth. She had passed away peacefully from a heart attack. Initially, Brian remained in London but – after a few months – joined his daughter, who had migrated to New Zealand. Recently one of his granddaughters wrote that he had passed away. To my satisfaction, she described him as Grampa.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 11: Peppi's Demise and Funeral</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:35:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peppi did not mention Anna again. Neither did he refer to his will. At our next reunion the sun was shining bright and the breeze was light and soothing. Shortly after I returned to Singapore I found a concise message on my answering machine. Lucy asked me to return her call as soon as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I stared apprehensively at the telephone. Snippets of conversations and fleeting images from my encounters with Peppi ran through my mind. When I sensed I was in control of myself, I picked up the receiver and dialled the number I had come to know so well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 11: A Posh Kumsits</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:29:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-11/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-indulgence-and-old-songs">1. Indulgence and Old Songs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For the next few minutes Pilkin and I watched as the waiter cleared the dishes and smartened the table by brushing the crumbs into a silver tray. After a quick glance at my host, who signified his approval with a nod, he uncorked another bottle of wine and then placed the dessert menu in front of us. Sighing, Pilkin ordered Zimmes, an East European sweet made of carrots. I knew he would have preferred a créme caramel but, after meat, a milk based dish was proscribed for four hours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 11: Curtains</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-11/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:00:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>During my twenty years in Australasia, I had visited Singapore regularly. Adjusting to my new teaching environment was therefore an easy task. News about Ranjan trickled in mainly through Allen, who – unlike Marcus in Melbourne – was an avowed enemy. Marcus had, invariably, viewed Ranjan’s activities supportively. Allen underscored the seedy aspect of what he chose to tell me. He remained unabashed when, on one occasion, I gave vent to my resentment of his bias.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 12: Anna's Revelation</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:36:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anna and Otto were waiting for us in the sitting room. I was struck by Anna’s appearance. The middle-aged woman who got up to meet us bore little resemblance to the charming little girl and vivacious teenager whose captivating smile livened up Peppi’s family album. I was put off by her severe expression, her firm mouth and her eyes – eyes devoid of mirth. Otto, in contrast, appeared friendly and well balanced and his eyes were warm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 12: Post Mortem</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:51:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-12/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-bushis-analysis">1. Bushi&amp;rsquo;s Analysis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>“Well, Bushi” said Pilkin when the glasses were empty, “it’s good to know that entre nous we’re still Bushi and Pilkin: never mind about that Professor Dr. Berger and the Rabbi Zohar stuff. So we have weathered the years! But now we have to turn to the awkward part of our reunion: the post mortem. You remember: we agreed to have it!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“So we did,” I nodded, “why don’t you start?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 13: Theophil's Outlook</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:37:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>On my last day in London, I had an early breakfast and, following a pleasant stroll on Hampstead Heath, decided to have a last browse in Kensington Church Street. Leaving the train at Notting Hill Gate, my feet soon led me to Theophil’s Antiques.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lucy had concluded the negotiations forthwith. The new owners transferred the stock in trade to one of their shops and removed the furniture. The building, which was to be put on the market following refurbishment, looked desolate. Gone were the tapestries, the illuminated books, the silver, the glass and the porcelain displayed in the show windows. The vacant rooms and bare floors, visible through the panes, announced ‘empty’. The signboard alone bore witness to the fact that this barren shell had once housed one of London’s famed antiques stores.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 13: Finale</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:53:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>Next morning I packed my suitcase, went for a walk and then had a light breakfast. When I stepped back into the lobby, the receptionist told me the room facing the Matterhorn was ready. After I settled in it, I took Pilkin’s gift out of the spacious pocket of my parka. Was it a paper knife or some other small Bezalel artefact? First to be revealed was a fine chamois sachet. Inside it was a velvet sheath, neatly tied with a maroon lace. When I opened it, my hand started to tremble. I was holding in my hand an exquisite religious object, delicately crafted in silver: a Mezuzah, traditionally mounted on the door post of Jewish homes in remembrance of the Exodus myth. Smilingly, I recalled the Mezuzah that had been displayed on front door of my parents’ home in Tel Aviv. It, too, was a fine piece, but not of the same quality as the work of art I admired this morning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 14: The Pact</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:40:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while we remained silent. He was watching me closely. I contemplated him with admiration. Despite his unappealing appearance I was mesmerised by his bright eyes. True, they looked straight through me and read my thoughts effortlessly and accurately, stripping me of all pretence. All the same, I sensed their warmth and was captivated by the understanding they reflected. I knew I was facing a being superior to me and realised I was in the presence of an intellect that dwarfed mine. Nonetheless, I was overcome by an intense feeling of brotherhood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 15: Aftermath</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:41:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>The driver of the van and his mate dismantled Peppi’s desk unceremoniously, hauled its three parts down the lift and returned for the armchair and stool. The former smacked his lips appreciatively as he reinserted the cork into the neck of the bottle of Slivovitz which I had asked him to take away with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I wandered through the empty rooms, scenes from my many encounters with Peppi and Lucy racing through my mind. It was only after I had pulled the front door shut that I noticed it was raining heavily. Instantly, I realised that I had left my umbrella in the stand in the entrance hall. Looking around me anxiously for cover, my mind strayed to Theophil. At the very same moment I heard a sharp sound and turned to see my umbrella hanging from the door handle. Had the men put it there?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Epilogue</title><link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/epilogue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:03:25 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/epilogue/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years later, Ranjan’s sad end was vividly drawn back to my attention. One day I received an email in which the sender, who signed himself as Chula Jeyaratne, asked me for lunch. Initially, I was unable to identify him. I then recalled that I had met Ranjan’s younger brother, whose name was Chula, during my first visit to Colombo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The man in his late middle age, who had arrived at the agreed venue before me, bore no resemblance to that unformed boy I had met years earlier. His black hair was laced with silver and his face was wrinkled.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>