<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to my collection of stories on Peter Ellinger</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to my collection of stories on Peter Ellinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:03:25 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: A Dilemma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 20:10:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My secretary had arranged the incoming mail in a neat pile. As I leafed through it, my glance fell on an envelope posted in Colombo. Was it a request for a reference from one of my recent Sri Lankan students? I was about to slice the cover open when Shamsiah’s call reminded me that my Banking Law class was to commence in five minutes. Reluctantly, I dropped the letter back on my desk, picked up my notes and hurried to my seminar room.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Above the Clouds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:57:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-an-extraordinary-catalogue&#34;&gt;1. An Extraordinary Catalogue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As  the  aeroplane steadied on its westward course, I  started  to  skim through  the papers respecting the  legal  entanglement  that required my presence in London. Conscience and professional integrity dictated that   I peruse the bundle meticulously. I owed this to the friendly  law firm  that was paying handsomely for my services and for the comfortable  seat in  the  business  class  section  of  British  Airways’  direct  flight  from Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: A Gifted Youth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:49:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My knowledge of Ranjan’s youth is based on what he thought fit to tell me and on occasional remarks of  his contemporaries. A model primary school pupil, a boy scouts leader and a fine cricket player were on the credit side. A tricky fellow, one ready to snitch when it suited him, and a  mercenary to boot, were remarks made by those who disliked him. One of them told me that Ranjan would display enthusiasm when he was the key figure in some sporting event, but often lost interest when it was the turn of others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Past Perfect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:59:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-a-confused-day&#34;&gt;3. A Confused Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill  Riggs  was  waiting for me at the arrival hall of  Terminal  3  at Heathrow Airport. He  was,  actually, looking fresher and more vigorous than he  had  ever appeared  in Singapore. For  a  short while we  gossiped  about  mutual  friends  in Singapore,  about  my forthcoming book and about his own work  in  his  London firm.  Then, as if by  prior arrangement, we turned to business. I started by expressing my doubts respecting the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: The City of the Lion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:50:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agnes turned out to be a vivacious English-educated Chinese, some five or six years older than Ranjan. A telephone call she received when I delivered Ranjan’s parcel convinced me that my friend was not the only man in her life. Out of curiosity, I accepted her invitation to a party in her flat but, in the event, left early as I found it difficult to fit with her guests. Still, before long I met colleagues, mainly from the English literature department, with whom I was able to mix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Along the Rhine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:04:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-her-loreley&#34;&gt;12. ‘Her Loreley’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A  classy BMW, booked by Yuan Ming in London, was waiting for us on  our arrival  in Cologne airport.  I was relieved when one of the firm’s  employees offered to drive us through the hectic traffic of the town to the shore of the Rhine.  A tour of the dome was complemented by our lengthy visit to  the nearby  Germanic  museum, a modern structure encapsulating  a  Roman mosaic. It was  laid bare in the bombing attacks of 1944 after being hidden under  the ground for over a thousand years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: A Trip to Oxford</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:51:33 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, I had proof of the validity of their assessment. Notwithstanding my heavy teaching load and other commitments in Singapore, I had been working steadily on my doctoral thesis. Our library’s holding were adequate for my research of the English and Commonwealth law in point but, as was to be expected, had few materials from other jurisdictions. To get them, I had to spend some time in Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Settlements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:07:14 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;14-exciting-auction&#34;&gt;14. Exciting Auction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You look refreshed,” said Bill Riggs when I arrived next morning in his office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thanks. And how does the case stand?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our  Judge  is  back in action.  In the   pre-trial conference,  he urged the parties to settle!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And have you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whitehead and Blackburn won’t let us,” he said, referring to the two  fighting cocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s  the  matter  with  those two?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They had a quarrel – a shouting match – over the  Wine Stewardship of their club. Since then they are not on speaking terms.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: End of Era</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:52:09 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the surface, my friendship with Ranjan remained intact. Inwardly, though, I had misgivings.  Jilting a girl was one thing; holding onto money given by the girl in anticipation of a union, put a different connotation on the episode. I knew for certain that, in similar circumstances, I should have restored the money to her family. Keeping it was both inappropriate and  improper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this score, Ranjan showed no remorse. Risking both his own savings as well as Lillo’s bequest, he continued to dabble in the local stock exchange.  Bank statements he showed me in confidence indicated that he was making  steady gains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: Ranjan&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:52:46 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my years in Wellington, I often soliloquised about Ranjan’s life. Years later, when we had returned to Singapore, I felt the need to clear my mind. My occasional talks with Tay Fung-Shuo, which I had  during my first period  in Singapore, threw no light on the episodes respecting Ranjan. Tay had remained tight lipped and, as soon as decorum permitted, changed the subject, usually by leading the way to some newly discovered antique porcelain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: An Aspiring Politician</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:55:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is time to turn back to my years in Wellington. The geographic remoteness did not distance Ranjan and me  from one another. We corresponded periodically but, of course, had less occasion for exchanges of views and of impressions than during our days in Oxford and in Singapore. Each was preoccupied with his own career. I tried hard to settle in the windy capital of New Zealand. My problems were related mainly to my family life and to the occasional hiccups of academia. Ranjan sought to rise in his home country. His new milieu  and environment were alien to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: A Spiteful Reaction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:56:31 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ranjan was rising in politics, continued to make a fortune at the Bar and laid the foundation for the great leap forward. He refrained from referring to his marriage but once mentioned in passing that there was no sign of a ‘family’. I drew my conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own life, too, continued uneventfully. Then, one day, Pat spotted an advertisement for a new Chair of Law at Monash University in Melbourne. She nagged me into applying and – with the help of Fortuna – I got the job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9: Jaffna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:58:57 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of my year of leave, we returned to Melbourne.  I had to complete a few additional years of service so as to secure an adequate retirement benefit. I assured Pat that, in due course, we would move back to Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this second spell at Monash, Marcus kept me informed about Ranjan. Politically, Ranjan moved from strength to strength. Within a few years, he became the President’s right-hand man. He was now tipped ‘the successor’ and, in his own way, wielded power and influence. But – all in all – he had remained a subordinate. The reigns were still in his superior’s hands. Occasionally, Australian television showed him in the company of other members of the Sri Lankan cabinet, assembled around their leader and ready to run his errands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Alfie&#39;s Verdict</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 12:59:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many years have passed since that fateful turn of events, covering Ranjan’s act of revenge and the atrocities committed in Jaffna. But even after Ranjan’s untimely death at the hand of a hired assassin, my mind kept mulling through the episode. One evening I slid to my antiques room in Singapore so as to discuss the matter with Tay Fung-Shuo – now replaced by his porcelain Doppelgänger, dubbed Alfie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So you do old antiques dealer honour of unexpected visit,” Alfie chided me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:10:37 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The penultimate draft of &lt;em&gt;The Hidden Rooms&lt;/em&gt; was completed when I was in my sixties.  In 2010 I  self-published it as part of &lt;em&gt;The Scales of Fortuna&lt;/em&gt;. Nowadays, when I am in my nineties, I have revised it with a view to uploading  in my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has happened in the decades that had elapsed. Following my return to Singapore, I maintained a regular correspondence with Brian Davies. Before long, he made his exit from the City and, as planned, opened an art dealership with his daughter’s friend.       All seemed clear on his horizon. His business was thriving. Then, one sad day, I received the death notice of his wife, Ruth. She had passed away peacefully from a heart attack. Initially, Brian remained in London but – after a few months – joined his daughter, who had migrated to New Zealand. Recently one of his granddaughters wrote that he had passed away. To my satisfaction, she described him as  Grampa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11: Curtains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my twenty years in Australasia, I had visited Singapore regularly. Adjusting to my new teaching environment was therefore an easy task. News about Ranjan trickled in mainly through Allen, who – unlike Marcus in Melbourne – was an avowed enemy. Marcus had, invariably, viewed Ranjan’s activities supportively. Allen underscored the seedy aspect of what he chose to tell me. He remained unabashed when, on one occasion, I gave vent to my resentment of his bias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:03:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/peter-blog/novellas/a-candid-obituary/epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years later, Ranjan’s sad end  was vividly drawn back to my attention. One day I received an email in which the sender, who signed himself as Chula Jeyaratne, asked me for lunch. Initially, I was unable to identify him. I then recalled that I had met Ranjan’s younger brother, whose name was Chula, during my first visit to Colombo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man in his late middle age, who had arrived at the agreed venue before me, bore no resemblance to that unformed boy I had met years earlier. His black hair was laced with silver and his face was wrinkled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
