<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reunion in Zermatt on Peter Ellinger</title>
    <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reunion in Zermatt on Peter Ellinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:53:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Arrival and Vigil</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 12:12:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-pension-kegel&#34;&gt;1. Pension Kegel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  electric car of Pension Kegel was waiting for me outside  the railway  station.  Fastening my scarf to keep out the crisp air of  a  typical dawn in Zermatt, I walked briskly up the platform and got in. As often before, I breathed the clean air  in deeply and with satisfaction. The absence of fuel driven motorcars was a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electric car driver,  who was  also  the  sole concierge of the  modest  establishment,  manoeuvred  his ramshackle vehicle adroitly through the narrow and winding lanes  of  my favourite Swiss  resort. I observed with a grim smile  that  for him, too, time had not stood still: his wrinkles had deepened and his hair had turned  silver grey. Bestowing on me the smile reserved for old customers,  he carried my suitcase up the stairs  to the reception counter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Planning a Historical Trial</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 12:14:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-josephus-and-the-great-jewish-revolt&#34;&gt;1. Josephus and the Great Jewish Revolt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I  doubt if Pilkin and I would have become mates   had  it not been for the Josephus Flavius trial staged by TA.1 in 1950. Although the War of Independence was by then long over,  Israel had not fully recovered from its economic and social effects. Commodities were scarce, prices were high  and the black market was booming. One of the objectives of Israeli schools of that period  was to turn its pupils into good citizens. Nobody was held in  greater contempt than a traitor to the struggle for the survival of the two years old nation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Learning the Law: Courts and Keren</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:13:45 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-we-attend-trials&#34;&gt;1. We Attend Trials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our  teacher  granted  us leave to attend court  hearings during  three  mornings dominated  by  classes  on  science. As Pilkin’s home was  not  far  from  the District  Court  building,  I went to pick him up early in  the  morning.  His mother’s  unadorned  poorly furnished flat on the top floor of a  run  down apartment  block made me gape. Obviously, his late father had not  left  them well  off. Embarrassed, I remembered Shosh had told me that, when  opportunity presented  itself, Pilkin and his young brother, David, carried out odd  jobs, such  as  deliveries, doubling up for newspaper vendors  and  occasional  home repairs. To my relief, Pilkin appeared unaware of my consternation. He watched with satisfaction  as I sipped the cup of hot and aromatic lemon tea his mother brought  me  and then  showed  me, with relish, his small but neatly organised  and  catalogued collection of coins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: The Josephus Trial</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:18:24 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I stretched myself comfortably on the bed in Pension Kegel in Zermatt, I kept  musing on my days with law firms and in universities. The foundation was laid  when, some three years after our initial encounter, Jacob Keren accepted me as a trainee. During the years I had spent with him, I learned much about  the law and  life in general.  By the time I left Israel, I had – under Keren’s guidance – developed a penchant for rescuing losing cases. That gift stood me in good stead during my years in Wellington, in Melbourne and in Singapore. All the same, my greatest success as a lawyer remained the trial  of Josephus Flavius in TA.1. Smilingly, I allowed myself to stray back to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: Early Years of Friendship. Pilkin&#39;s Heart Attack</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:19:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-a-budding-actor&#34;&gt;1. A Budding Actor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most regards, my success at the  trial  remained  a Pyhrric   victory. In the minds of the public, a worn cliché – “there is no smoke without fire” – defeated the logical argument. Josephus’ reputation remained as tarnished as ever. All the same, the historical trial of the long deceased historian constituted  a milestone in my career. Recalling it vividly during the dinner in Pension Kegel, some 45 years after the event, I concluded that the prelude  to the  great football match remained my  neatest achievement as a lawyer.  Single handed, I had won a battle that took place in an unsympathetic, even prejudiced, forum. Relaxing in Pension Kegel’s comfortable sitting room as I sipped a cup of aromatic coffee, I  mused on the episode and on the major effect it introduced  into  my erstwhile  lonesome existence: it cemented a bond between Pilkin and myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: Our European Trip</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:25:40 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-turkey&#34;&gt;1. Turkey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took us just over two years to save enough money. By then,  I had nearly finished my pupillage at Jacob Keren &amp;amp; Associates. Pilkin was slogging his way through his course at the Hebrew University and making every effort to shine on the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sipping a second glass of Cognac in the comfortable dining room in Pension Kegel, I recalled with amusement the unadorned berth my friend and I had taken on a Turkish ship sailing along the coast of Anatolia to Istanbul. It had been a no-frills trip marked by the need to economise. Yet, despite the parsimony dictated by our circumstances, our adventure  had left a deeper impression on me than the many high class tours and neatly planned excursions I had enjoyed later on in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: The Rendezvous</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:13:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-leah&#34;&gt;1. Leah&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early next morning, as the Matterhorn emerged in its splendour at the first rays of light, I resumed my vigil. Soon the electric cars started to arrive from the station but the patrons alighting  from them bore no resemble to my Pilkin of old. By 9.00 a.m. I threw in the towel. For all I knew, Pilkin might be snoring  in a comfortable room in some other hotel in Zermatt. Despite his formidable size, he constituted a needle not easily pinpointed in the haystack of the buoyant flow of tourists in the popular resort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: Intermezzo</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:16:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-meandering-about-life&#34;&gt;1. Meandering About Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I relaxed over lunch in a booth table in the mountain establishment on the Riffelalp, I kept reflecting on the forty years that had passed since the days spent by Pilkin and me in Zermatt. Professionally, I had made it. Although I was not destined to develop into a court room virtuoso, it had not taken me long to rise from strength to strength in Jacob Keren &amp;amp; Associates. Initially, I had worked with Hannah Hod,  the scion of an old Jewish family from Hamburg, who was a few years my senior. We won many of our cases and, in the process, developed a good, even if unromantic, friendship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9: Reunion. Reminiscences</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:18:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-we-meet&#34;&gt;1. We Meet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My neatly tailored three piece grey suit,  white shirt and fashionable tie did little to ease the pounding of my heart as I followed the concierge through the imposing dining room of the Zermattschein. Would I recognise Pilkin as soon as I spotted our table? Had his appearance changed as much as mine?   For all I knew, he could by now have become the heart and soul of parties given in his honour by a group of jolly grandchildren!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Pilkin&#39;s Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:26:35 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-pilkins-remaining-years-in-israel&#34;&gt;1. Pilkin’s Remaining Years in Israel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the waiter wheeled in a trolley with our  main courses. As soon as he departed – having  re-filled our wine glasses – I said: “Well, now it’s your turn, mon Cher Pilkin – or shall I say Rabbi Zohar?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At you service,” he smiled benignly. “And ‘Pilkin’ will do!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So out with it!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Where shall I start?” he asked, smacking his lips  as he savoured the excellent goose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11: A Posh Kumsits</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:29:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-indulgence-and-old-songs&#34;&gt;1. Indulgence and Old Songs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next few minutes Pilkin and I watched  as the waiter cleared the dishes and smartened the table by brushing the crumbs  into a silver tray. After a quick glance at my host, who signified his approval with a nod, he uncorked another bottle of wine and then placed the dessert menu in front of us. Sighing, Pilkin ordered Zimmes, an East European sweet made of carrots. I knew he would have preferred a créme caramel but, after  meat, a milk based dish  was proscribed for four hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12: Post Mortem</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:51:32 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-bushis-analysis&#34;&gt;1. Bushi&amp;rsquo;s Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, Bushi” said Pilkin when the glasses were empty,  “it’s good to know that entre nous we’re still Bushi and Pilkin: never mind about that Professor Dr. Berger and the Rabbi Zohar stuff. So we have weathered the years! But now we have to  turn to the awkward part of our reunion: the post mortem. You remember: we agreed to have it!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So we did,” I nodded, “why don’t you start?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13: Finale</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:53:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/reunion-in-zermatt/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next morning I packed my suitcase, went for a walk and then had a light breakfast. When I stepped back into the lobby, the receptionist told me the room facing the Matterhorn was ready. After I settled in it, I took Pilkin’s gift out of the spacious pocket of my parka. Was it a paper knife or some other small Bezalel artefact? First to be revealed was a fine chamois sachet. Inside it was a velvet sheath, neatly tied with a maroon lace. When I opened it, my hand started to tremble. I was holding in my hand an exquisite  religious object,  delicately crafted in silver: a Mezuzah, traditionally mounted on the door post of Jewish homes in remembrance of the Exodus myth. Smilingly, I recalled the Mezuzah that had been displayed on front door of my parents’ home in Tel Aviv. It, too, was a fine piece, but not of the same quality as the work of art I admired this morning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
