<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Hidden Rooms on Peter Ellinger</title>
    <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Hidden Rooms on Peter Ellinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:10:37 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Above the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:57:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-an-extraordinary-catalogue&#34;&gt;1. An Extraordinary Catalogue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As  the  aeroplane steadied on its westward course, I  started  to  skim through  the papers respecting the  legal  entanglement  that required my presence in London. Conscience and professional integrity dictated that   I peruse the bundle meticulously. I owed this to the friendly  law firm  that was paying handsomely for my services and for the comfortable  seat in  the  business  class  section  of  British  Airways’  direct  flight  from Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Past Perfect</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 19:59:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-a-confused-day&#34;&gt;3. A Confused Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill  Riggs  was  waiting for me at the arrival hall of  Terminal  3  at Heathrow Airport. He  was,  actually, looking fresher and more vigorous than he  had  ever appeared  in Singapore. For  a  short while we  gossiped  about  mutual  friends  in Singapore,  about  my forthcoming book and about his own work  in  his  London firm.  Then, as if by  prior arrangement, we turned to business. I started by expressing my doubts respecting the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Along the Rhine</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:04:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-her-loreley&#34;&gt;12. ‘Her Loreley’&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A  classy BMW, booked by Yuan Ming in London, was waiting for us on  our arrival  in Cologne airport.  I was relieved when one of the firm’s  employees offered to drive us through the hectic traffic of the town to the shore of the Rhine.  A tour of the dome was complemented by our lengthy visit to  the nearby  Germanic  museum, a modern structure encapsulating  a  Roman mosaic. It was  laid bare in the bombing attacks of 1944 after being hidden under  the ground for over a thousand years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Settlements</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:07:14 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;14-exciting-auction&#34;&gt;14. Exciting Auction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You look refreshed,” said Bill Riggs when I arrived next morning in his office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thanks. And how does the case stand?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our  Judge  is  back in action.  In the   pre-trial conference,  he urged the parties to settle!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And have you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whitehead and Blackburn won’t let us,” he said, referring to the two  fighting cocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s  the  matter  with  those two?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They had a quarrel – a shouting match – over the  Wine Stewardship of their club. Since then they are not on speaking terms.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 11:10:37 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breaddcrumbss.github.io/peter-blog/novellas/the-hidden-rooms/epilogue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The penultimate draft of &lt;em&gt;The Hidden Rooms&lt;/em&gt; was completed when I was in my sixties.  In 2010 I  self-published it as part of &lt;em&gt;The Scales of Fortuna&lt;/em&gt;. Nowadays, when I am in my nineties, I have revised it with a view to uploading  in my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has happened in the decades that had elapsed. Following my return to Singapore, I maintained a regular correspondence with Brian Davies. Before long, he made his exit from the City and, as planned, opened an art dealership with his daughter’s friend.       All seemed clear on his horizon. His business was thriving. Then, one sad day, I received the death notice of his wife, Ruth. She had passed away peacefully from a heart attack. Initially, Brian remained in London but – after a few months – joined his daughter, who had migrated to New Zealand. Recently one of his granddaughters wrote that he had passed away. To my satisfaction, she described him as  Grampa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
