<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>The Devil in Munich on Peter Ellinger</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/</link><description>Recent content in The Devil in Munich on Peter Ellinger</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:41:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1: Reminiscences at the Station in Munich</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:18:14 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-the-platform-phenomenon">1. The Platform Phenomenon&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An event that took place in an underground-train station in Munich’s inner city had far reaching effects on the life of three persons: Peppi Stölzl – who rose thereafter in the world, became Sir Joseph-Dieter, Freiherr von Stölzenfeld – my late father, Robert Berger, known to friends as ‘Tommy’, and myself, Peter Berger, a mendicant professor who eventually settled in Singapore but travelled from time to time to London where eventually I met Peppi,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Mayhem and the Brotherhood of Man</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:23:14 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-the-locum-and-his-provocation">1. The Locum and his Provocation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After his reunion with Peppi, Dad had to travel to Italy. On his return to the old Bavarian capital, Dad took the train to Peppi’s station. Upon disembarking, he saw a strange figure mounting the podium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Where is Peppi Stölzl?” he asked the new incumbent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’m standing in for him this morning,” came the laconic reply.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I was hoping to see him here today.” Dad let his disappointment show.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: An Antiques Dealer in Munich</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:25:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-3/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-peppis-second-career">1. Peppi’s Second Career&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Following this encounter, Peppi started to go from strength to strength. His friendship with Dad remained intact, with each rejoicing at the other’s success. Their paths, though, did not cross again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Dad, the turning point was Russia’s withdrawal from Vienna in 1951. He and Peppi saw in it Theophil’s hand. Modern historians have come up with a more mundane explanation: Russia’s bridgehead in Vienna was of no military, political or tactical advantage. Austria’s unilateral declaration of neutrality – the price exacted by the Russians for their withdrawal – constituted a safer barrier against Western aggression than the sparse Red Army troops stationed in the old Habsburg capital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4: Anna's Defection and Helga's Death</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:26:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-4/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-annas-change-of-heart">1. Anna&amp;rsquo;s Change of Heart&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Anna was growing up. Occasionally she brought up subjects she had never raised before. Some related to human relationships. Others touched on faith and religion. Peppi recalled, in particular, a conversation they had one evening on their way home. They had been shocked to witness a van knocking a young man off his motorcycle. Once they had recovered, they continued their walk home. Then, unexpectedly, Anna asked: “Papa, does the Good Lord really exist?”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 5: Peppi's Last Days in Munich</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 21:37:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-5/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="1-sale-of-the-munich-business">1. Sale of the Munich Business&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Peppi decorated his new flat to his own taste. The Albigensian panel painting, which prior to Helga’s death had been kept out of sight, now adorned the wall of his study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shortly after moving into his new flat, Peppi received two letters. Anna wrote to say she had completed her secretarial studies and had accepted a well-paid post in one of Bremen’s leading industrial firms. She thanked him for his support in the past but emphasised that she was relieved to be able, at long last, to ‘stand on her own two feet’. Peppi’s reply, congratulating her on her achievement, was laconic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 6: Peppi Moves to London (Theophil's Antique)</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:27:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peppi arrived in London just in time to celebrate his seventy-fifth birthday. Despite his advanced age, Peppi adjusted to his new environment in no time. Soon he felt at home both in Hampstead and in Kensington Church Street. With the joint efforts of father and daughter, Theophil’s Antiques continued to flourish. Within two years, they had taken over all the shopping space in the house. To facilitate further expansion, Peppi purchased the building.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 7: Peppi's Delve Into Porcelain</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:27:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Theophil’s Antiques continued to go from strength to strength as did Peppi’s fame. He was delighted when one of London University’s Colleges conferred on him an Honorary Doctorate. Another source of joy was Lucy’s appointment as an Adjunct Professor in another College. Initially, Peppi was concerned about her drained appearance when she returned home after her classes. To his relief she soon adjusted to her position, carrying on her new duties without neglecting their shop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 8: Peppi Meets Peter Berger</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:29:42 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>Initially, Peppi’s new venture attracted limited interest. London was blessed with a number of well-established shops specialising in European ceramics. In addition, many experienced collectors tended to acquire their pieces at auctions. Peppi, though, had learned to bide his time and could afford to be patient. The modest profit made by the end of the second year of the ceramics venture signalled that he was on the right track. A few months thereafter his enterprise gained further momentum when two adjacent porcelain shops closed down. Peppi acquired the stock-in-trade of both dealers and, as anticipated, their customers turned to his shop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 9: Encounter with Mr. X: Alias Friedrich Duval</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:31:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>My friendship with Peppi and Lucy filled a gap in my life as well as in theirs. Usually, I packed my suitcase with joy for the flight to London and with a glum face for the return trip back to my barren home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could fill a whole ‘bundle’ with anecdotes from my visits to London. Despite his advanced age, Peppi had retained his zest for life and his keen intellect; and he was full of fun. Lucy too was an excellent companion. Occasionally, when Peppi was reluctant to go out in the evening, the two of us went to the West End on our own. After the show, we would have a snack or a drink in one of the numerous bars where, often, I listened with admiration to Lucy’s witty critique of the performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 10: Peppi's Last Years and Dillma</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:33:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peppi, Lucy and I used to take long walks on Hampstead Heath or in Kensington Gardens. From time to time, when the weather permitted, I hired a car and drove us down to St Albans, Windsor or Oxford and, on many a fine spring day, to Hampton Court. Like most visitors, we continued to get lost in the maze and invariably had to wait, with the rest of the crowd, to be guided out by one of the warders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 11: Peppi's Demise and Funeral</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:35:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peppi did not mention Anna again. Neither did he refer to his will. At our next reunion the sun was shining bright and the breeze was light and soothing. Shortly after I returned to Singapore I found a concise message on my answering machine. Lucy asked me to return her call as soon as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I stared apprehensively at the telephone. Snippets of conversations and fleeting images from my encounters with Peppi ran through my mind. When I sensed I was in control of myself, I picked up the receiver and dialled the number I had come to know so well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 12: Anna's Revelation</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:36:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anna and Otto were waiting for us in the sitting room. I was struck by Anna’s appearance. The middle-aged woman who got up to meet us bore little resemblance to the charming little girl and vivacious teenager whose captivating smile livened up Peppi’s family album. I was put off by her severe expression, her firm mouth and her eyes – eyes devoid of mirth. Otto, in contrast, appeared friendly and well balanced and his eyes were warm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 13: Theophil's Outlook</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:37:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>On my last day in London, I had an early breakfast and, following a pleasant stroll on Hampstead Heath, decided to have a last browse in Kensington Church Street. Leaving the train at Notting Hill Gate, my feet soon led me to Theophil’s Antiques.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lucy had concluded the negotiations forthwith. The new owners transferred the stock in trade to one of their shops and removed the furniture. The building, which was to be put on the market following refurbishment, looked desolate. Gone were the tapestries, the illuminated books, the silver, the glass and the porcelain displayed in the show windows. The vacant rooms and bare floors, visible through the panes, announced ‘empty’. The signboard alone bore witness to the fact that this barren shell had once housed one of London’s famed antiques stores.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 14: The Pact</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:40:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while we remained silent. He was watching me closely. I contemplated him with admiration. Despite his unappealing appearance I was mesmerised by his bright eyes. True, they looked straight through me and read my thoughts effortlessly and accurately, stripping me of all pretence. All the same, I sensed their warmth and was captivated by the understanding they reflected. I knew I was facing a being superior to me and realised I was in the presence of an intellect that dwarfed mine. Nonetheless, I was overcome by an intense feeling of brotherhood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 15: Aftermath</title><link>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:41:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://peter-ellinger-blog.com/novellas/the-devil-in-munich/chapter-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>The driver of the van and his mate dismantled Peppi’s desk unceremoniously, hauled its three parts down the lift and returned for the armchair and stool. The former smacked his lips appreciatively as he reinserted the cork into the neck of the bottle of Slivovitz which I had asked him to take away with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I wandered through the empty rooms, scenes from my many encounters with Peppi and Lucy racing through my mind. It was only after I had pulled the front door shut that I noticed it was raining heavily. Instantly, I realised that I had left my umbrella in the stand in the entrance hall. Looking around me anxiously for cover, my mind strayed to Theophil. At the very same moment I heard a sharp sound and turned to see my umbrella hanging from the door handle. Had the men put it there?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>